<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.emmanueltouzery.projectpad</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>Projectpad</name>
  <summary>Projectpad allows to manage secret credentials and server information that you need to handle as a software developer or sysadmin.</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Projectpad allows to manage secret credentials and server information that you need to handle as a software developer or sysadmin. List of servers, list of point of interests on those servers (applications, log files, databases, servers). It will securely store passwords and keys. It will also allow you to run commands (locally or on SSH servers), open terminals on remote SSH servers, and so on. The data is securely stored on-disk using SQLcipher, which uses 256-bit AES. The database is password-protected, but you can store the password in your OS keyring. Since the database is encrypted, you can put it in your dropbox (or similar account), to share it between computers.</p>
    <p>Projectpad's target audience are people who today have to use several tools to do their work effectively: a keepass-like application, a series of text files with notes, and a few shell scripts. Instead of that, projectpad offers a streamlined, integrated solution.</p>
    <p>Projectpad consists of two applications:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>the GUI projectpad application, which allows you to enter/edit data, search it, open websites and so on (included in this flatpak);</li>
      <li>the command-line ppcli application, which allows you to run commands, connect to servers, open files of interest and so on (must be installed separately, see https://github.com/emmanueltouzery/projectpad2).</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/emmanueltouzery/projectpad2/pics/gui1.png</image>
      <caption>Main Window</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/emmanueltouzery/projectpad2/pics/notes.png</image>
      <caption>Markdown notes</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/emmanueltouzery/projectpad2/pics/gui2.png</image>
      <caption>Search mode</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/emmanueltouzery/projectpad2/pics/gui_dark1.png</image>
      <caption>Dark mode</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/emmanueltouzery/projectpad2/</url>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="violence-cartoon">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-profanity">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">none</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <releases>
    <release version="3.0.1" date="2025-07-05">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Smarter sorting for search results</li>
          <li>Control-E shortcut to edit the current item</li>
          <li>Control-Y shortcut to copy any visible password</li>
          <li>Focus the closest widget when opening search results</li>
          <li>Shortcuts dialog</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.0" date="2025-06-04">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Complete rewrite of the GUI to gtk4 and libadwaita</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.3.1" date="2021-12-28">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>fix styling of the search bar -- buttons and entry are now properly linked</li>
          <li>Nicer GUI to add server and project items: buttons with description instead of radio buttons</li>
          <li>Notes: hide the 'Copy code block' button when switching notes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.3.0" date="2021-09-10">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Upgrade dependencies, mostly relm 0.21, gtksourceview 3->4</li>
          <li>Code cleanups</li>
          <li>When a server item group changes, must refresh the whole list</li>
          <li>Server link: display details about the server we link to in the header</li>
          <li>Fix bugs: "Copy Database" used to copy the username, copy POI path used to copy the text</li>
          <li>Ability to move project items: servers, server links, project notes, project point of interests can now be moved from one project/environment to another one. Server links to the moved item will continue working.</li>
          <li>Fix hidpi issues with icons in projects and search</li>
          <li>Notes: on hover a button will appear on top of note code blocks to offer to copy their contents to the clipboard, and a new context menu entry will offer to copy code blocks too</li>
          <li>Headers: server 'text', server item 'text' are now displayed inline in headers if they're populated</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.2" date="2021-02-11">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix export bug: used to complain the filename didn't end in .7z even if it did</li>
          <li>Export: add a "confirm password" entry</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.0" date="2021-01-14">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix export if the user typed a filename not ending in .7z</li>
          <li>Search view: displaying preview of shortcuts when holding ALT or CTRL wasn't reliable</li>
          <li>Project search filter (prj:) - allow quotes for project names with spaces</li>
          <li>Minor cleanups</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.1.0" date="2020-12-23">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Support for import/export with project granularity to 7zipped YAML files</li>
          <li>A server link can now link to a specific group within a server</li>
          <li>Ability to search within notes also when editing</li>
          <li>New shortcut to edit a note: ctrl-e</li>
          <li>Scrolling to server item: more precise scrolling</li>
          <li>Refresh versions of dependencies</li>
          <li>Bugfix: shortcuts in the search view were tied to e and y instead of ctrl-e and ctrl-y</li>
          <li>Bugfix: project note groups were not included in the group entry completion</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.2" date="2020-11-22">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Prevent from changing the password to an empty password</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.1" date="2020-11-21">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix bug: if the user would close the password dialog on first run, the app would consider the DB set up when it wasn't</li>
          <li>fixes #1 prevent empty passwords in projectpad because moving between encrypted and plain DBs is non-trivial</li>
          <li>easy way to go to the database file from the preferences dialog</li>
          <li>display infobar when copying from the search view</li>
          <li>ctrl-y will copy a single server password from the search view</li>
          <li>aesthetics: don't insert a separator in the menu if there are no items after it</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2020-11-12">
      <description>
        <p>First release of Projectpad 2.0</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <kudos>
    <!--
    GNOME Software kudos:
    https://gitlab.gnome.org/GNOME/gnome-software/blob/master/doc/kudos.md
    -->
    <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
    <kudo>HiDpiIcon</kudo>
  </kudos>
  <developer_name>Emmanuel Touzery</developer_name>
  <update_contact>etouzery@gmail.com</update_contact>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.github.emmanueltouzery.projectpad.desktop</launchable>
</component>
